本教程中我们将展示如何
In this lesson we're going to show how to
导入给定素材 特别是粒子
take the content examples that are given specifically the particle example
and maybe add it to a project that basically already exist.
So then we can take the particles and we can view them in the scene.
So to get started, I've already download the Game SDK sample project that shown right here,
and it shows that it's installed.
So the first thing we need to do is actually target this project at where it resides.
So we're gonna reveal in the explorer, if I bring that up, we can see
that this project actually resides in the C root
CRYENGINE Launcher\Crytek\GameSDK_5.0
and then this is your actual game folder.
So to take a previous to project,
what we're gonna do is step back,
and we're going to click Add Existing project.
Once we click this, we'll get a little prompt
and it allows us to browse for the folder.
If you remember we said that it was in the C root,
so if we go in here, we can see that we have CRYENGINE Launcher\Crytek\GameSDK_5.0,
and then GameSDK is what we want to target.
We're gonna click OK, and now we have added an existing project, it's all new.
But say we wanna add another level to an existing project that we got, say in the sample project.
So, to do that,
let's go ahead and close this,
and we're gonna target the GameSDK project specifically in this path,
open the sample content,
if we go to content examples, GameSDK,
we can see that we have Assets,
and then we have Particles and we have Levels.
So let's go inside of here, because I don't wanna load up everything,
and I'm gonna grab the contentExample
and drag that in,
and I'm gonna that the particles and drag that in.
So now we're ready to fire up the launcher, because we've put everything into our project.
If we just click here,
now we have the engine open, and click down here.
Since it's ready, I also I think I click twice,
so we can remove that, doesn't matter if you open another instance thought.
To File->Open->contentExample,
we're gonna look specifically for the PARTICLE_CONTENT_EXAMPLE.
So if I double click this,
it'll load the file with the level.
And then when it happened, we can see that we have all of the particles lined up to be ready to be used,
and they all have a name, say 3d rotation, volume, and pretty much, you can go and explore these
with the PARTICLE_CONTENT_EXAMPLE. To access the actual particle editor,
you wanna go to Tools->Particle Editor,
and it will automatically load the particles over here.
And you can choose anything, like 3d rotation,
just right here, and hit this for a second,
move that over there,
bring this up, scroll up a little bit,
and we can see this is the actual chain, it allows for the 3d rotation to work.
Bring it up a little closer,
and now we can see exactly what it looks like in the editor,
we can see what it looks like in the graphic editor for the particles.
And I hope you can explore this projects and
get them up and running for your own development, because
particle effects 2 for our DX12 branch has been a great boost compare to the old particle system,
and I think everybody's gonna like it.
翻译：他出院了