For this final video in the series, we're gonna cover some placement of objects,
and then we're also going to cover maybe
placing an AI character inside the level,
and also dragging out a navmesh to be able to give it interaction.
So to begin, what we can do is we can focus on the idea of placing a hut,
because this was what, I guess if I lived on an island, I figured that I would be building a hut.
So we go to the create objects tab and let's go to architecture,
buildings and we can go to the forest_cabin.
Let's double click this and bring this out into our level.
Now, I don't know exactly which side the door is on,
obviously this one,
and we can pull this back into
the actual woods.
Now this would be one of those cases where you need to cull wherever the vegetation is,
so let's go ahead and close material editor, level settings,
when go back to the vegetation editor,
and let's find the actual bush.
So maybe we just get rid it of bush, so it's out of the way quickly.
So now we have a nice little cabin,
and I think that we would like a nice little dock,
not exactly sure where it is, inside of this,
so maybe we can type it in, plus we can search.
We open the assets/objects/props/
maritime/wooden_dock,
So, that's cool, we have a nice little dock,
and we can click and add,
so let's click the 2 key, we can add that.
And let's keep in mind one other thing is we can actually duplicate this dock,
we duplicate it
can open up this, let's change the vegetation editor,
just go ahead and close all these.
And now we can change the dock inside of here,
maybe it's something else that we would like.
Let's go ahead and change one more, you can quickly test things
that otherwise you may not have an idea of what it is.
So I like this right here, this dock and maybe
we can use this one as the end piece.
This other one looks kind of big, so
to start out
I know that this will probably be the end, just because
of how it set up, and then this is going to be the beginning.
If we snap these together,
leave a height discrepancy,
we can pull this up
and now they're all one.
So if I control click and select both of them,
I can go into my Level->Group,
and we're gonna group these objects, we call this dock.
The reason we did this is because now we can select both of them together
and they'll scale as they should.
So it's a nice little way of how to set up everything
to work for you and not against you.
So now we have the dock right here,
but maybe it's not exactly set up for a little path.
So what we can do is go back to our create object,
we can go to miscellaneous, let's choose road,
but before I do that, I want to make sure that I have terrain snapping on.
I can turn off the grid snapping as well, this won't matter as much.
So I'm gonna click the road
and I'm click here in front of the door,
click here and we'll end it there.
So let's turn on helpers,
so we can see where the road is,
you notice that they got kind of twisted up,
that's probably because I didn't have it selected properly.
Let's go ahead and do geometry anyways,
so with that selected, we can click the forest road,
it's going to be very short,
we can go in and we can change the width to maybe 2,
and what we need to do now is we need to actually select the material.
So if we click in the override material,
we're gonna wait for it to boot up,
we go to the materials/roads,
and let's go ahead and do
probably a road... a road_gravel,
So now we have a gravel road which...
here's something that is very interesting regarding roads is you can align them,
so if I take off my align to terrain
and I push this down just a little bit,
and align the height map,
now we have a custom height map that drops with it from the actual door.
So now we've created the house, we've created the path,
we have grouped the dock together,
what else can be done?
Well, we said that we wanted to add an AI character to this,
so if I go back to my entities
and I choose AI, we'll choose a character here,
and we will make sure that we have align to
geometry on.
By double click,
and we'll hold... bring him into the scene.
So we have our AI character here,
and if we were to click play,
he would drop down and you would see him kind of walk around,
it doesn't really walk yet, because he needs a navmesh, but he...
he will play some animation, an idle animation, where he's just standing there,
but we can turn around though, so we can see what he's doing.
So now we have our AI character which we can put him on this path, I guess,
and what we need to do now is actually give him a valid navmesh to navigate around him.
So in order to do this, I'm actually going to change something,
I'm going to go into the display, and I'm going to choose to hide the ocean.
So in hiding the ocean, I can actually see the border or the boundary
of where exactly the terrain is,
because as we remember,
it's not very big and navmash is going to require this,
so what we wanna do now is go back,
we'll go to AI, we're gonna choose navigation area,
we'll make sure that we have snap to
geometry on,
we'll click navigation area and we will begin drawing it out, so
it's just going to look for points,
and we'll drag it around this area.
We'll see that it's processing the navigation mesh,
and what we need to do is actually move it upward,
because right now, the navigation mesh is a little low.
So we'll let it process once again and you can see the actual terrain of where the navigation mesh is being drawn.
So we're still a little too low,
I'm gonna go back to displaying the ocean,
and you can see it's just kind of a guess and check game,
we're eventually... we're gonna get to the point where
we're not actually drawing the navigation mesh into the ocean,
but we still can get it on the dock and surround the areas.
Ok, so...
now we have a navigation mesh that's been drawn out in our level,
we have an AI within it and this AI can actually operate wherever he is,
and he can even come down to the dock and that's what's nice about this,
and keep in mind maybe you need to change it
and the navmesh will update accordingly,
so it's not like it's completely dependent on this and it only generates and then you're stuck with that,
so it's just something that you need to remember as far as generation.
So I think I'm gonna end the video right here,
and what we've done is we've laid down a dock, we've
laid down a road for a path, we've stuck the building there,
we've actually stuck an AI in there,
we've generated a navmesh inside of our island that the AI can operate in.
翻译：他出院了