For this video, which is going to be a few different sections
will be about creating your first level,
in this case, with the first one, we're going to create the level,
we're going to create the terrain, we're going to paint the terrain,
and then we're going to apply vegetation, all within this one video.
So, it's only take about 10 minutes, and let's get to it.
To start, we'll go to File->New,
and we'll call this one training_FirstLVL,
and we'll keep in the levels folder, then we're gonna choose a small heightmap resolution,
which means the terrain size will be 128 meters in all directions.
We're going to keep the texture dimensions at 4k,
and not worry about the other settings, because they have to do with compression,
and are out of this scope of this video.
We're gonna click ok,
and now we're basically have our level which is 128,
and if we come down here, we have our ocean.
So, what we need to do is we need to define the height of this terrain, so it matches the height of the ocean.
Let's go into Edit->Set Terrain inside of the Terrain Editor box,
and we're gonna go to setting the terrain to something about 50 meters high.
We'll notice that nothing happened, and this is because we need to actually generate the terrain again.
So let's bring the feature size down to about... 3.6 is fine,
we can lower the bumpiness all the way,
and everything else will keep at basic.
So if I click ok,
we now have a nice little terrain.
I think I can actually get something a little better, so you can always go back and generate more,
over and over again that if you wanna see the variation that you can create.
So let's go ahead and see what we can get again.
So we keep getting blobs and blobs,
eventually, I want them will be about what I'm looking for.
And, this will do. I kinda just want a more than just one, and kind of relatively small.
So now we have our ocean, and we have our island,
because that's what we're gonna do, is create a desert island, it's the easiest thing that you can do
with the most aesthetically pleasing results quickly.
What I need to do now is get rid of some of these humps, they're just too big.
So, inside of the terrain editor, I can go to sculpt, and then we're choose Flantten,
and if I were to just start painting,
it would be kind of random and that's not what we want.
We're going to do is lower this down to 10 on the radius, and you'll see down here in the height,
we can actually have the option to pick.
What we're actually going to do is to pick it dynamically by holding down the Ctrl key.
So if we keep our eyes peeled on this, so we click down here on the edge.
Maybe right there, we can see that it's switching based on where we click.
So let's keep that up about 18.6,
what we can do now is we can come in here and know that wherever we sculpt,
it's not gonna be below that level.
So we keep that, maybe do some over here,
but now what if we want to actually smooth this out.
So we can press the Shift key,
we now have the ability to smooth it out on everything we just sculpted.
So maybe we wanna smooth everything down,
we can kinda have something that's a little bit better flattened that way we have a better beach.
So now that we have basically our landmass declared,
we need to create a terrain texture to cover it, because right now
the checkerboard look just isn't working.
So we go to paint, and I right click and create a layer,
let's call this one sandDry.
And we're gonna choose the texture to be Textures/defaults, so we're just gonna choose white,
because we want to paint the actual texture of sand.
So we need to choose a material now,
and what we're gonna do is go to materials/terrain and choose beach_white_sand.
And what we can do is we can paint this in if we want,
so if we start painting, you'll notice right away, we get a lot of sand everywhere,
and we can actually even change the color of it,
drop it down and just grayscale, and you'll notice it's darker,
so maybe that's what we want.
And this doesn't look bad actually.
So, instead of painting everything, we can actually cheat.
We can right click this layer, and say Flood Layer,
and then automatically we have sand everywhere
which works pretty well.
The one thing that I don't have is, I want to have a wet sand.
It doesn't look exactly right when we see some shadowing
but we don't see any change in how the sand kind of washes away.
So what we can do is create another layer,
and call this one sandWet.
And we can change the texture again, to be Textures/defaults/white again.
And then this time we're gonna choose a different material.
So we go to materials/terrain
and choose beach_white_sand_wet.
We can go ahead and start painting this.
So what I'ma do is I'm going to paint it in so we can see what we have,
it's a little bright, so if I can control it back,
drop it like we did to the other,
and that'll work.
So all I did was calibrate it,
because we're actually going to do a constraints procedurally painted.
Like before, with the sculpt, we can go back and we can flatten,
but the key thing understand this is we're actually going to pick the height of how far it influences.
So the water is here, let's say we influence up to this point here.
So let's try 16.5,
so going back to sandWet,
we can set the minimum height with the maximum height.
Let's go ahead and put this to 16.5 at the maximum height,
and we leave the min height at zero.
So if I right click this now and flood layer,
you'll notice that it's painted all around the edge of the actual ocean.
Alright, I mean, you couldn't get any better because we're
able to paint whatever we what along the edges
and not have to worry about whether or not it works,
because we procedurally generated it based on a height.
So now we've done that,
we're ready go in and create some vegetation like we said.
So this right here is gonna require us to go to tools,
and we'll go to the vegetation editor,
and let's snap this over the other editor,
so I'm gonna bring this out a little bit, we're gonna create some groups.
The first group I'm gonna do is I'm gonna add the trees group.
This is gonna be the easiest one to do,
and probably the most densely populated one,
and then we're gonna do another group called bushes,
and that'll be the lower.
So if we go into this trees,
we're gonna actually click up here, these are the same icons that we had before,
and we can click and add the actual trees we want.
So what I want is I wanna have a palm tree,
and I'm gonna select all the palm trees in this group.
And if I scroll this open, we can see all of them,
and you would have the same selections on all the trees,
but this time I'm actually gonna select the group,
and you can influence all the children of the parent group.
I'm going to change the size variation to be about point seven pass the size,
we'll do random rotation,
and then in the bending, we're just gonna set that to 1,
we're gonna come down to the density and we're gonna change this to about 7 or so.
Keep in mind this is the density between the actual instances,
so the lower of the actual level,
it's counterintuitive, you would think,
ok, density, I want it to be closer together.
So what would I do, I wanna create more objects and you wouldn't increase it,
but the density actually relies on the distance between those.
So the higher the value the actually more spacing you get.
We're gonna come in here as well and change this to 18 on the elevation minimum,
and then we're also going to change the cast shadow
and the receive shadow, we'll keep the min spec set to low.
So let's save this real quick,
and then what we're gonna do is right click and distribute the selected vegetation objects and see what we get.
So now we have a lot of trees,
all over the place that we just randomly generated,
and to be honest it doesn't look that bad,
it's kind of a little bit too much,
so maybe I want to go back and change it.
Well, there are different options that you have here, we can set our trees,
and we can click the erase button,
and we can start erasing them manually which works quite well.
It doesn't matter they were procedurally generated,
you can come in and change that all around.
You can also have the option to maybe hide the certain species,
so maybe that's what we want.
We can do this, maybe hide that,
and this looks a little bit more manageable as far as what the island is doing.
So we have all there trees in place,
and we have these other trees that maybe we can just
completely get rid of if we want in.
So we go down to remove,
so now we don't deal with them at all.
So let's look at this again, what if we want to just change this and distribute some more,
so we can distribute more objects,
and this is the nice idea of being able to use like
procedurally or dynamically changeable amounts
just based on by clicking a button instead of going in and painting,
and like I said before, we can go in, we can paint the objects as well.
So the question is what exactly do you want in your trees
and how exactly do you want them to be dynamically pushed around.
We're gonna go back and we're actually going to do brushes now.
So I'm gonna add some brushes
and natural brushes,
and we're gonna choose greenfernbush.
We're gonna select all of these,
and we're gonna do some of the similar things that we did on the other, point 7,
rotation, we're gonna set the bending to 1,
we go ahead and move down, let's set the
elevation minimum to 18,
cast shadow, receive shadow,
and then for the most part I think will be set
to go ahead and distribute.
So,
the one thing that I realized I didn't set right before I click this was I didn't set the density.
So you can see how much it actually matters.
With the density that's not declared, we now have brushes everywhere,
which maybe what you wanted, but it's not what we wanted.
So pressing ctrl+z, I can come down into the brushes,
and I can set the density to something a little more manageable,
so let's do that to 6
and see what gets laid down.
So now we can see that we have quite a few more brushes,
but maybe we want to keep adding to them.
So,
we have all these objects that we would be able to use,
and now going into select, I can actually come in and change these too.
So it's just a feature like the paint and remove
that you would be able to select the objects that you're wanting to change,
and being able to change them dynamically.
If I want
all these objects to be able to scale down,
we have the option to do so.
And like before, we can also go in shrink this down
and maybe remove some species.
So you never know exactly what you want for something,
maybe you want a lot of brushes or maybe you don't.
We go in and we can
erase objects which we're gonna do in this case.
We're gonna set something up so we can have like a little
bridge later, stages of this.
But for right now, we have the vegetation, we have just laid it,
and I think I'm gonna end the video there
just before we start getting in to the actual global illumination and set in the clouds up,
and then sticking an object right here and maybe a nice little
em...
dock that we could have out into the ocean, so
this is the vid showing you how to set up the vegetation,
how to set up everything dynamically
and change around the actual parameters on the fly quickly,
which is the most important part.