For this lession, we're going to talk about how to customize your UI inside of CRYENGINE.
By default, this is the UI that most people see.
We actually should step back and...
these icons are the first thing that you would see in the creates objects tab.
We have Properties, Terrain Editor, the typical Perspective and Layer or Level Explorer,
we have a Console, and then up here we have the Tool Bar and Menu.
So, maybe you just happen to remove everything.
so let's go ahead and close out the Properties, Console, the Level Explorer,
and now the one thing that seems to be catching up a lot of people is I can close the Perspective viewport.
So now we have the most clean, unadulterated version of CRYENGINE interface you can have.
In order to get things back, you're gonna need to go to the Tools pane
which inside of here we can start with the Viewport->Perspective.
This bring us back the viewport that we had before,
and if we move it around, we can see that we kind of get a hotbox in the middle.
We know that we want this to be right in the center,
so if we go and hover right over this tab, we can just bring it right back.
The same could be set for the actual Level Editor, and let's do the Properties next.
So if I drag this over to the right,
I'm able to add it to this pane without disturbing the menu.
I'm gonna do the same for the Create Object tab,
and like before, add it this way.
And then finally, to get it all back, we're gonna go to the Level Explorer,
in this time, we're actually going to add it on the bottom.
So now we pretty much got back our default setting, we don't have Terrain Editor, but...
overall, this is the same layout that typically you would start with.
So let's go ahead and go up to Layout, we can see that we can save this layout.
So just to go a little crazy and just understand maybe, what we're doing.
Let's move this out and we will save this layout
inside of Crytek and we'll call this one layoutTutorial
and we'll export that.
Now appear, let's go ahead and reset the layout.
We're just come back to this default thing,
let's go ahead and close everything once again,
so then we're left with our default,
We're gonna go ahead and load our layoutTutorial.json file.
We will import that, and you notice that,
it's come back and allows you to do all the customization like before.
The next thing that we can do is actually come up to the Toolbar, so in this blank area,
if we right click, we can see that we have a lot of bottoms that aren't exactly exposed by default.
We click the Audio, now we have a bunch of audio bottoms, we also have Constraints.
And you'll see that we have this little dot next each one of them,
and you can actually move it around, it's very very portable to wherever you want.
So, this is basic understanding of how you can manipulate just the toolbar and then also
the entire viewport and maybe how you can reset it and load
or just even save your viewport that you like with the layout you want,
and in future ones, we'll go over the console variables,
and look at how we can customize commands or even macros
to be able to give us a more customized and streamlined workflow.